# Vernon R. King, III

Having felt an earnest call to ministry since college, I have been preparing for both foreign missions and domestic church ministry through internship opportunities, academic study, voracious reading, intense dialog, and a foray into electronic publishing while simultaneously pursuing a career in software development. Although my primary focus has been church health, including church planting and church strengthening, I have also been gifted in personal counseling and have experience in adoption ministry. I hope to transition into vocational ministry upon completion of my M.Div.

I affirm the <u>Abstract of Principles</u>, the <u>Baptist Faith and Message 2000</u>, the <u>Chicago Statement on Biblical Inerrancy</u>, and the <u>Danvers Statement on Biblical Manhood and Womanhood</u>.

### **Education**

Southeastern Baptist Theological Seminary | Wake Forest, North Carolina

Currently pursuing Master of Divinity in Christian Ministry

Anticipated graduation: December 2014

GPA: 4.0

Southwestern Baptist Theological Seminary | Fort Worth, Texas

Coursework toward *Master of Divinity in Missions* 2009 – 2011

GPA: 4.0+

Texas A&M University | College Station, Texas

Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering

May 2007

GPA: 4.0, summa cum laude

Relevant Experience

Pillar on the Rock | Ecclesiological Online Magazine

Co-founder and Editor, www.pillarontherock.com

2009 - 2011

Wrote and edited articles promoting healthy local churches:

- Article reprinted in B&H book, <u>Preach: Theology Meets Practice</u>, by Mark Dever and Greg Gilbert
- Edited 100+ articles; Authored 50+ articles (www.pillarontherock.com/search/label/PJ King)
- Grew the writing team to include six authors

New Song Church | Windhoek, Namibia

Missionary Intern

May 2007 – August 2007

Residential intern with an IMB missionary church and youth ministry:

- Assisted in the leadership and administration of a 150+ youth outreach program
- Helped host two American short-term mission teams for two weeks each
- Provided technical support for church, youth ministries, and camp

# Vernon R. King, III

## **Professional History**

Southeastern Baptist Theological Seminary | Wake Forest, North Carolina

Software Developer May 2013 – Present

FTS International | Fort Worth, Texas

Lead Software Developer May 2011 – January 2013

Deloitte Consulting | Dallas, Texas

Software Consultant, Homeland Security January 2011 – May 2011

FIS | Oklahoma City, Oklahoma

Senior Programmer Analyst October 2009 – November 2010 September 2007 – October 2009 Programmer Analyst II

### **Personal Background**

Contact

Family 81 McDowell Dr.

Kathryn Rose (spouse), Vernon Ray, IV (11), Wake Forest, North Carolina 27587 Brooklyn Leigh (8), Emma Grace (4), Seth

vernon.king@outlook.com | (817) 458-8174 Christopher (1). Website: http://www.vernonking.org

Some of our children were adopted in 2011. Sermons: http://www.vernonking.org/sermons/

Blog: http://www.adoptedbytheking.com

#### References

Benjamin H. Arbour, Ph.D.

Andy Winn, M.Div.

Nathan Finn, Ph.D.

Elder, First Baptist Church, Durham Mentor and Friend Associate Professor, Southeastern Seminary (979) 574-1300 (919) 280-4309 benarbour03@yahoo.com

nfinn@sebts.edu

Ryan Hutchinson, M.Div.

hutchinson@sebts.edu

Associate Pastor, First Baptist Church, Durham Elder, First Baptist Church, Durham

(919) 452-1427 EVP for Operations, Southeastern Seminary

andy.winn@fbcdurham.org (919) 761-2200